Irving Steinberg Sudbury Slide Collection
City of Greater Sudbury Archives
Irving Steinberg Sudbury Slide Collection
[between 1955-1965]
007
18 photographs: col, mounted on slides
City of Greater Sudbury Archives 5 Lindsley Street Falconbridge Ontario P0M 1S0 Telephone: 705-688-3965 Fax: 705-699-1919 Email: archives@greatersudbury.ca
Steinberg, Israel "Irving"
Box C-005
Israel "Irving" Steinberg was born January 16 1919 in Peterborough Ontario. Shortly after his birth he moved with his parents, Joseph and Leah Steinberg and his sister Rose Steinberg, to Sudbury Ontario where his father founded Toronto Bargain Stores. The Steinbergs lived in Sudbury until 1932 when they moved to Toronto. Joseph Steinberg died on July 14 1963, and Irving Steinberg as executor of his estate retained property in Sudbury until 1968 when it was expropriated by the city as part of a downtown urban development project. Irving Steinberg passed away on March 1, 2011.
published
Charles Levi (Archivist and ACA member)
Colour slides depicting various sights in and around Sudbury in the late 1950s and early 1960s. Some of the slides are numbered suggesting they were part of a larger slideshow on Sudbury. Slides may have been collected to support claims related to the city expropriation of properties on Borgia Street in the 1960s. Slides were produced by various studios in Ontario.
Photographs; Buildings and structures; Community life; Sudbury, Greater
ACC2009-007, Charles Levi
Further accruals are not expected.
Earl Levi recieved the slides as power of trustee for Irving Steinberg. He gave the slides to Charles Levi who donated them to the archives.
Steinberg sous-fonds, Levi/Smith/Weinstock/Steinberg papers in possession of Charles Levi, 2009.
- Sudbury High School, [between 1955 and 1965]; 007-1; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide (Box C-005)
  published
  Item is a picture of a high school taken from the schoolyard.
  Education; Sudbury, Greater
- Woolworth Building Sudbury, Ontario, 1961; 007-2; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide; According to the Leeds 1000 Islands Municipal Heritage Committee, Rideau Air Photos Ltd, based in Seeley Bay, Ontario, operated from about 1957 to about 1961 under partners D.G. Willis and Jack Wyatt. (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of an office building with "Woolworths" "Crown Life", and "Confederation Life" signs visible. People, the crossing street, and cars also can be seen in the image.
  Sudbury, Greater
  Item has been digitized. Prints of image may be requested. Email archives@greatersudbury.ca for more information.
- 2. Durham St. Looking North, Sudbury, Ontario - R.B.L. P.O. Box 394, Sudbury, Ontario, Canada, [between 1955 and 1965]; 007-3; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of a city street, cars, and two children jay-walking. A "Hotel Coulson" sign is clearly visible.
- 6. Lisgar St. Looking North Sudbury, Ontario - Robert Brown Ltd - Duplicate Benjamin Film Labs., [between 1955 and 1965]; 007-4; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide; Gordon Brown, Robert Brown's son used to take professional photographs of Sudbury and sell them at Robert Brown Jewelers. Image used with permission of Robert Brown Jewelers. (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of a city street, cars, and buildings.
- 11. Residential District Overlooking Lake Ramsey with Gen. Hosp. at right Sudbury., [between 1955 and 1965]; 007-5; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of houses, trees, Lake Ramsey, and the Sudbury General Hospital taken from an elevated area.
- 17. A Pouring Molten Slag at Sudbury, Ontario - Robert Brown Ltd., July, 1962; 007-6; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide; Gordon Brown, Robert Brown's son used to take professional photographs of Sudbury and sell them at Robert Brown Jewelers. Image used with permission of Robert Brown Jewelers. (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of six rows of molten slag taken at night.
- 20. St. Elizabeth School of Nursing Sudbury Ont. - Nickletone Processing Sudbury Photo Service Sudbury, Ontario, [between 1955 and 1965]; 007-7; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide; Sudbury Photo Service operated until about 1980 as a business which sold photography equipment and supplies and developed photographs for local retail stores. (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of a building taken from the rear.
- 23. Prince Charles School, 1 of 64 Elementary Schools in Sudbury, Ontario, [between 1955 and 1965]; 007-8; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of a school taken from a street. A child is also in the photograph.
- 26 Sudbury Public Library, 1961; 007-9; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide; According to the Leeds 1000 Islands Municipal Heritage Committee, Rideau Air Photos Ltd, based in Seeley Bay, Ontario, operated from about 1957 to about 1961 under partners D.G. Willis and Jack Wyatt. (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of the Sudbury Public Library taken from MacKenzie Street. A 'Red Ensign' flag flying.
- 27. Federal Building, Sudbury, Ontario, July, 1962; 007-10; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide; Gordon Brown, Robert Brown's son used to take professional photographs of Sudbury and sell them at Robert Brown Jewelers. Image used with permission of Robert Brown Jewelers. (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of a downtown Federal Government building taken from across the street. Cars are also visable.
- 28. Hockey Arena Sudbury, 1961; 007-11; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide; According to the Leeds 1000 Islands Municipal Heritage Committee, Rideau Air Photos Ltd, based in Seeley Bay, Ontario, operated from about 1957 to about 1961 under partners D.G. Willis and Jack Wyatt. (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of the Sudbury Community Area, sign advertising "Bingo Wednesday August 2" and "Horticultural Show August 12 and 31."
- 38. Four Schools, Public Library and Part of St. Joseph Hospital, Sudbury - Photo Copyright Rideau Air-Photos Ltd Seeley's Bay, Ont. Can, 1961; 007-12; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide; According to the Leeds 1000 Islands Municipal Heritage Committee, Rideau Air Photos Ltd, based in Seeley Bay, Ontario, operated from about 1957 to about 1961 under partners D.G. Willis and Jack Wyatt. (Box C-005)
  Item is picture of buildings including the Sudbury Public Library and four schools taken from behind a fence, cars, and a roadsign advertising "Carpark" with rates. The schools shown on the hill from left to right are College Notre Dame at s s Levis, Mary Mount High School at 165 D'Youville Street, and St. Elizabeth School Of Nursing (nine floor building) at 30 Ste-Anne Road. On the left side of the library is St Aloysius at 164 Mackenzie Street and the Sudbury High School is accross the street at 154 College Street.
- 42 Bell Park Sudbury, Ont. - Nickletone Processing Sudbury Photo Service Sudbury, Ontario, [between 1955 and 1965]; 007-13; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide; Sudbury Photo Service operated until about 1980 as a business which sold photography equipment and supplies and developed photographs for local retail stores. (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of a crowd in Bell Park with some people sitting on the grass and others in the water wading and swimming. Trees, a walkway, and boats can be seen in the distance.
- 43. Looking north toward downtown Sudbury, Ontario, Jul. 1962; 007-14; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture taken from an elevated area of trees, buildings, and a railyard.
- 60. View of Sudbury, Ont from one of Many Rock Hills. - Nickletone Processing Sudbury Photo Service Sudbury, Ontario, [between 1955 and 1965]; 007-15; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide; Sudbury Photo Service operated until about 1980 as a business which sold photography equipment and supplies and developed photographs for local retail stores. (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture taken from an elevated area of trees and buildings.
- 62. Durham St. Looking South, Sudbury, Ontario. - Nickletone Processing Sudbury Photo Service Sudbury, Ontario, [between 1955 and 1965]; 007-16; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide; Sudbury Photo Service operated until about 1980 as a business which sold photography equipment and supplies and developed photographs for local retail stores. (Box C-005)
  Item is picture of Durham Street, cars, people, a "Rexall" sign and the "Royal Bank of Canada" visible.
- 74. The Pelletizing Plant of the Lowphos Iron Mine at Sudbury, Ont. - Nickletone Processing Sudbury Photo Service Sudbury, Ontario, [between 1955 and 1965]; 007-17; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide; Sudbury Photo Service operated until about 1980 as a business which sold photography equipment and supplies and developed photographs for local retail stores. (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of the inside of a factory, machinery, and a worker.
- 75. The Kalamazoo Vegetable Parchment Co. Paper Mill at Espanola, Near Sudbury, Ont. - R.B.L. P.O. Box 394. Sudbury, Ontario, Canada, [between 1955 and 1965]; 007-18; 1 photograph: col, mounted on slide (Box C-005)
  Item is a picture of a factory complex and mill stream.